It was the stone, as red as blood,
which promised to turn suffering to delight, bring victory to battle,
and life back to the dead.
In reverence, people referred to it
as "The Philosopher's Stone."
How can this be possible?
Brother...
This is the answer we finally arrive at
after seeking it for so long?
How can living people be the ingredients for a Philosopher's Stone?
And so many of them, to boot!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
M-Major, p-please, wait a minute!
Major Armstrong!
Um, right now, they appear to be tired, so we probably shouldn't disturb them.
What? They're tired?
In that case, I'll invite them to have dinner,
which will invigorate them.
Ah, no! Um...
Right now, the two of them are resting.
I will tell them that
you came by, Major.
I see. I guess there's nothing I can do if they're sleeping.
God must really hate people who have committed taboo.
Just when we think things are
within reach, they run away from us.
Then it repeats.
And when they're finally within our grasp, we get kicked down by them.
Is this going to happen
for our whole lives?
Brother...
I thought that once we found the Philosopher's Stone,
our wish would be granted.
We'll find it, that's for sure!
After all, we're trying this hard.
They may say that you're a dog of the military
and that you've sold your soul
for special privileges,
but haven't we persevered without admitting defeat?
And so...
And so, we'll find it for sure, Brother!
Brother...
Let's try starting from square one again.
I've had enough.
There's a chance that
we misread something.
I said I've had enough.
But what if we try re-reading it?
We might discover something new!
I'm going to give it a shot. Let's keep trying!
I told you, I've had enough!
Brother...
Is something the matter?
I'm sorry. I don't even
want to look at it anymore.
Brother...
So, that's it, then?
You won't regret
having given up here?
Is what you've been searching for something you would abandon this easily?
Stop going on when you
don't even know the half of it.
I know. I know that you guys are seeking the Philosopher's Stone
and that it is made by
sacrificing living people.
I knew it was rude,
but I allowed myself to listen in.
If you've listened in,
then you must know
that it won't do any good to investigate any further. Just leave us alone!
You really are a child, huh?
You're scared, right?
That the answers might disappear?
You don't want to acknowledge that everything you've gone through this far
might be in vain, right?
Am I wrong?
Isn't it okay if it doesn't
mean anything?
Verifying whether or not this means anything is worth something, if you ask me.
What you're seeking isn't
anything all that simple, right?
Why don't you keep trying
a little longer, Edward-san?
You're right...
It's not as though the answers are going to change
just because I chuck it
all along the way.
Brother!
We've come this far!
How can we end it all halfway?!
We're going to
see it to the end!
Let's do it, Al!
Mm-hmm!
Marcoh-san's research is sound in theory.
However, it still didn't result in a perfect Philosopher's Stone.
There still might be other possibilities.
Yeah. I'm going to verify the truth of Marcoh-san's theory with my own eyes.
Truth?
The genuine truth behind truths...
Behind... truths...
That's it! There's something else!
According to this data,
a considerably large facility would be needed to create a Philosopher's Stone.
There are currently four alchemy laboratories under the military.
Among those, Doctor Marcoh was assigned to the 3rd Laboratory.
I went around to all of the laboratories in the city,
and there wasn't any research
all that remarkable going on there.
Huh? What's this?
Ah, in the past,
that was the 5th laboratory,
but it was closed down,
and is deserted now.
There's a risk of it collapsing, so it was made off-limits.
It's there!
Look.
There's a prison next to it.
Central 2nd Prison.
What about it?
With people being the ingredient for a Philosopher's Stone,
what if they did their research there because it was the easiest place to procure them?
You don't mean, they used prisoners?
Yeah.
If they didn't execute
condemned criminals
and instead used them as live materials, that would explain it.
Who's in charge of
the laboratories?
That would have been
Brig. Gen. Basque Grand.
And he was killed by Scar
some time ago.
Brother...
We've got no choice.
How about we check things out directly?
Mm-hmm.
J-Just a moment!
From here on,
this is grown-ups' work.
Besides, Scar is still after you.
It's too dangerous for you
to go walking around outside.
Yeah, but still...
We will investigate the 5th Laboratory. You wait here, please.
If we learn anything,
we will report it to you.
If you please...
Brother...
So be it. Okay, it's up to you.
We'll ask you to handle it.
Right! Leave it to us!
Lt. Colonel Hughes,
I'm finished writing down the
court record for case number 3263.
Oh, is that right?
Sorry, hang on a minute.
Well, let's have you continue on with case number 9572, if you would.
They're going to use it in a trial tomorrow, so put a rush on it.
Okay...
What's the matter?! Are you tired?!
No, not particularly!
Look here! This one is
a special swimsuit version!
What do you think?
She's so cute, it just melts your heart!
Just looking at this, the fatigue just flies away, doesn't it?
How about it? Hm? Hm?
Yes...
It does, doesn't it?
Um, Lt. Colonel...
My daughter is such a little healer.
Lt. Colonel! What is the problem there?!
So, did you find Scar's body?
Not yet, huh?
All right. As for the matter of us sending security to the library,
hurry and take care of that for me.
Oh, I've been introduced to quite a find here.
I owe one to Ed for her.
Tripwire alarms?
For a building that isn't being used, the security sure is tight, huh?
This is getting more
and more suspicious.
All right, let's go around back.
Al...
Ups-a-daisy!
I hate to say it,
but it's times like this
that I'm glad I don't have my flesh-and-blood arm and leg.
Same here.
This entrance is locked up tight, too, huh?
Brother, over there...
Looks like it goes
all the way inside.
Al, you wait here.
Will you be all right
by yourself?
All right or not, your huge size won't fit through here, right?
Okay, I'll be back in a bit.
I'm not this big
because I wanted to be!
This is Lt. Maria Ross.
Major Armstrong, please.
What is it, Lieutenant?
Major, I need to talk to you
about something.
Hey!
Contact the Command Center at once,
and call in reinforcements!
Yes, sir!
I have no business with you.
Where is Fullmetal?!
Two of you stay here!
We're going up another stairway!
He's going up to Edward-san's room!
So Fullmetal knew about this too?
Don't move, Scar!
Lieutenant!
Where are Edward-san
and his brother?
Please look at this.
Those boys...
The town of Liore...
has been dealt with
all neat and tidy.
There's no longer anyone there who knows too much.
You don't say. Nice work, Envy.
Things are going well here too.
The Fullmetal pipsqueak has caught wind of the laboratory, hasn't he?
Shouldn't we dispose of him
before it gets out to the military?
If we're going to kill him,
let me do it!
Hold on. That boy might just grant us what we want.
If we're going to kill him, it won't be too late to do so after that, will it?
Well, it's fine with me as long as it doesn't throw a wrench in the works.
Although, it seems doubtful that
he would ever arrive there safely.
I told them not to lay a hand on those two, but it is concerning.
They are idiots, after all.
If it looks to be too troublesome, dispose of the whole lot of them.
I know.
Damn, this is narrower than I thought.
Damn it all, if I were normal-sized,
I wouldn't have gotten through here.
It's a good thing I'm so little.
Augh! No, it's not!
The lights are on...
So they're not currently using it, huh?
Bingo!
Wh-What the?!
For them to go this far, they must really not want anyone getting close.
Sounds interesting!
I'll take them on!
Hey! Aren't we under orders not to lay a hand on them?
I don't care about that.
I can't rest until I've carved them up!
Wait! There are two in our quarry. There are also two of us.
I won't allow you to
have them all to yourself.
Dammit! This thing is relentless for being just a ball!
I-It really is a good thing
I'm so small...
Why, you! This is a pain!
Come on in, they're saying?
Nice of you to come.
I welcome you.
You don't look very welcoming.
I am he who was entrusted to guard this place.
For the time being,
you may call me Number 48.
Number 48?
It's been so long. I'm delighted to be able to go against someone so capable.
You have run out of luck
by coming up against me.
Do not think ill of me, kid.
And you, don't think ill of me for being the kid who defeated you.
Brother sure is taking long. What could he be doing?
Nice. You move well for your size.
That's more like it.
Who are you?!
I should respond when asked who I am, huh?
My name is Number 66.
Although, that's just what they call me at work.
Number 66?
Yes. I do have my own, proper name as well,
but if you heard it, you'd be
so surprised you'd wet yourself.
I'll tell you when I finish you off.
You say you guard this place, right?
There's a little something I'd like to ask you.
If you can defeat me,
I will tell you anything.
Right, then...
Let's see how good you are!
You're fast!
Your false arm is steel up to
the shoulder, is it? Even so...
my beloved sword will pierce even steel!
You've gotta be kidding!
If I bust it again,
Winry's gonna kill me, you know!
Let's see...
Oops...
His reflexes...
Why, you!
What?!
You brat!
He's...
the same kind of
armored body as Al?!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 20: "Soul of the Guardian"
We've cried a lot, laughed a lot,
and seen hell.
These memories are not false.
I am human!